sonlight.com 2001-06-04

# Sonlight Curriculum :: Privacy Policy

> Revised September 2, 2000
> 
> ### We Respect Your Privacy
> 
> We realize that, for some of our customers, **our discrete use of your personal information is—or could be—quite literally, a matter of life and death.** For that reason, **we always have maintained, and pledge in the future always to maintain our customers’ privacy to the highest degree possible.**
> 
> In sum: both on- and off-line, we use (and will use) whatever information we collect **solely to fulfill our obligations to you** as a customer, **and to improve our services in the future**. **We share no information with any outside agencies or persons whatsoever except on a strict “need to know” basis** to fulfill our legal and moral obligations to you, our customer. 
> 
> The following privacy policy statement explains in detail what information we collect, how we use that information, and your options about the way we collect and use your information. 
> 
> ### Privacy Policy Table Of Contents:
> 
>   * We Collect Minimal Information
>   * We Use Personal Information Only for Order Fulfillment and Communication
>   * We are Committed to Security
>   * We are Committed to Your Children's Privacy
>   * Some Technical Details on the Information We Collect
>   * You May Access or Correct Any Information We Collect
>   * Please Contact Us With Any Questions or Concerns About Our Policy
> 

> 
> #### We Collect Minimal Information
> 
> Depending on what you do and where you go on our website, we may collect the following information. 
> 
> **You can order our products and services on the web order form.** When you order, we need both contact information and financial information. We use contact information, such as home address, email, and phone number, to get in touch with you (perhaps to clarify a ship to address, to make sure you want duplicate items, or to answer any question you may have), and to ship your order. We only use financial information to bill you for any requested products or services. 
> 
> **We offer public forums** on our site for people to discuss homeschooling in general and Sonlight Curriculum in particular. We offer a variety of forums for a variety of needs. Each forum is periodically moderated to ensure currency, pertinence, and good taste. Please remember that any information you share on our forums is public information, so use caution in disclosing personal information. Although we moderate these forums, we are unable to delete or modify information until after it has been posted. 
> 
> **Our occasional online surveys** ask you for contact information (like your email address) and demographic information (like your zip code, Internet use patterns, age of children, etc.). We use the information from our surveys to improve our understanding of our customers’ general needs and to send you specific information about our company. We may contact you either to make sure the information is accurate, or to answer any questions collected from the survey. Furthermore, you may always remove your information from our system. (See You May Access or Correct Any Information We Collect below.) 
> 
> #### We Use Personal Information Only for Order Fulfillment and Communication
> 
> Sonlight needs some personal information from you when you order. We use that information only to complete your order and to track your order history with Sonlight. We do not share this information. 
> 
> If you provide any information about someone else (say, if you wanted to order a gift for a friend), we only use that information to ship their books and to confirm delivery. Again, we do not share this information. 
> 
> We use return email addresses only to answer the email we receive. We do not share email addresses with outside parties. We store these addresses as part of your customer record. 
> 
> If you want to receive our catalog, please fill out a survey on our website. If you want to receive periodic updates about our products and services, please subscribe to our email list. We use this information only to provide you with the desired catalog or updates. 
> 
> In order to improve our website’s design, we compile information from the general movements of our visitors. This compiled information shows what areas are of greatest interest to our visitors. The compiled information is not based on registration or surveys and is completely anonymous. 
> 
> These are the only ways we use personal information provided to us online. If you wish to remove your information from our systems, see You May Access or Correct Any Information We Collect. 
> 
> #### We are Committed to Security
> 
> We have advanced security to ensure only authorized persons can access your information. We secure a portion of our website with the latest encryption features from VeriSign Security. This protects your information, particularly your credit card information provided for purchases. We have a valid and current Certificate that attests to the security of our site. Our employees use IDs and passwords to further protect access to your information. 
> 
> #### We Are Committed to Your Children's Privacy
> 
> On our web site, we seek to protect the privacy of your children. Our Children’s Forum is for children under age 13, to allow them to communicate about homeschooling and Sonlight. This forum is periodically moderated to keep the topics in good taste, related to homeschooling, and current. Any information that your children disclose on this forum is public information. Therefore, please remind your children to use caution in what they share, especially personal information, since we are unable to delete or modify information until after it is posted. 
> 
> #### Some Technical Details on the Information We Collect
> 
> **We use your IP (Internet Protocol) address** (a numeric address that only computers read) to help us track your shopping cart when you order online. If necessary, the IP address could show us where in the website you are, although you would remain anonymous. We do not link your IP address to anything that personally identifies you. 
> 
> **If you visit the Sonlight Curriculum Online Purchasing System (SCOPS),** our system offers your computer a "cookie," a small file that includes bits of information that your browser (Internet Explorer, Netscape Navigator, etc.) can store on your computer. (By the way, only the site originating the cookie can read the contents of the cookie from your computer.) The "cookie" includes a unique, random user ID that will identify you anonymously to the SCOPS database. It also includes a copy of the password you choose if and when you decide to begin the purchasing process. The "cookie" enables SCOPS to keep track of your shopping cart so you don’t wind up having materials from other people’s orders in your cart, and they don’t find your materials in their cart. The "cookie" system is essential to the operation of SCOPS, so, though you can always refuse to accept a "cookie," if you do refuse, you will not be able to purchase online. 
> 
> **Our site contains links to other sites,** so you may easily access related content. We are not responsible for the privacy policies or content of any of these linked sites. We try to review these links periodically, and if you think any link is not up to Sonlight’s standards, please let us know so we can remove the link. 
> 
> #### You May Access or Correct Any Information We Collect
> 
> If you would like to be added to OR removed from our email address list, please send us an email, addressed to [email@sonlight.com](mailto:email@sonlight.com), with either the word **subscribe** or **remove** in the subject line. 
> 
> You may contact us at any time if you want to either remove your information from our web database, correct the information we maintain, or request that we no longer contact you. Ways to contact us include: 
> 
>   1. Send a general email to [main@sonlight.com](mailto:main@sonlight.com)
>   2. Subscribe or unsubscribe from our email list at [email@sonlight.com](mailto:email@sonlight.com)
>   3. Visit the URL [www.sonlight.com](http://www.sonlight.com/)
>   4. Mail to the postal address:
> 8042 South Grant Way, Littleton, CO 80122-2705
>   5. Call 303-730-6292
> 

> 
> In order to protect your privacy fully, we will confirm your identity before we grant access to any information, or before we make any corrections or deletions. 
> 
> #### Please Contact Us With Any Questions or Concerns About Our Policy
> 
> If you have any questions about either this privacy statement or the web site, please contact us: 
> 
> Sonlight Curriculum, Ltd. 8042 South Grant Way Littleton, CO 80122-2705 Phone: 303-730-6292 Email: [webmaster@sonlight.com](mailto:webmaster@sonlight.com)

|   

[Home](http://www.sonlight.com/index.html "Go To Sonlight Curriculum's Home Page") > Privacy Policy   

:::

**Search Sonlight:**

:::

as of 5/29/2001

:::

Go To:

"I love what Sonlight has put together. As a first time home schooler this program has been very easy to implement. Also using one basic for three kids has a wonderful way of bringing us together rather than each of us going our own separate ways."  
\- Kevin and Linda O., Hudson, WI, December 29, 2000.
